<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on @adnanrahic</title>
    <link>https://adnanrahic.com/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on @adnanrahic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Have questions? Shoot me an email, or hit me up on social media! This site was coded with &lt;3 by yours truly.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adnanrahic.com/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless with AWS - Image resize on-the-fly with Lambda and S3</title>
      <link>https://adnanrahic.com/post/a-crash-course-on-serverless-with-aws-image-resize-on-the-fly-with-lambda-and-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adnanrahic.com/post/a-crash-course-on-serverless-with-aws-image-resize-on-the-fly-with-lambda-and-s3/</guid>
      <description>Handling large images has always been a pain in my side since I started writing code. Lately, it has started to have a huge impact on page speed and SEO ranking. If your website has poorly optimized images it won&amp;rsquo;t score well on Google Lighthouse. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t score well, it won&amp;rsquo;t be on the first page of Google. That sucks.
TL;DR I&amp;rsquo;ve built and open-sourced a snippet of code that automates the process of creating and deploying an image resize function and an S3 bucket with one simple command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a serverless contact form with AWS Lambda and AWS SES</title>
      <link>https://adnanrahic.com/post/building-a-serverless-contact-form-with-aws-lambda-and-aws-ses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adnanrahic.com/post/building-a-serverless-contact-form-with-aws-lambda-and-aws-ses/</guid>
      <description>What if I told you it can be done with zero dependencies? Hope you&amp;rsquo;re up for a challenge because that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing.
This tutorial will cover the basics of both the front-end contact form, with vanilla JavaScript, and the serverless back end hosted on AWS Lambda. AWS SES is the service you use for sending the actual emails and trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s so incredibly simple the configuration takes 13 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>