<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vuejs on @adnanrahic</title>
    <link>https://adnanrahic.com/tags/vuejs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vuejs on @adnanrahic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Have questions? Shoot me an email, or hit me up on social media! This site was coded with &lt;3 by yours truly.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adnanrahic.com/tags/vuejs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless with AWS - Triggering Lambda with SNS Messaging</title>
      <link>https://adnanrahic.com/post/a-crash-course-on-serverless-with-aws-triggering-lambda-with-sns-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adnanrahic.com/post/a-crash-course-on-serverless-with-aws-triggering-lambda-with-sns-messaging/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a sucker for event-driven programming, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to continue reading. Today we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at triggering AWS Lambda functions from AWS SNS messages. I&amp;rsquo;ve covered a few interesting topics regarding serverless architectures and AWS already, but nothing like this yet. Dig down, and get ready. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
TL;DR  What are we building? What is AWS SNS? Build the API with the Serverless Framework Deploy the API to AWS Lambda Test the API with Dashbird  Note: All the code from this tutorial is already on GitHub if you want to check out the end result right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless-side rendering with Vue.js, Nuxt.js and AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://adnanrahic.com/post/a-crash-course-on-serverless-side-rendering-with-vuejs-nuxtjs-and-aws-lambda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adnanrahic.com/post/a-crash-course-on-serverless-side-rendering-with-vuejs-nuxtjs-and-aws-lambda/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s a mouthful of a title right there. Don&amp;rsquo;t let it scare you away. What it boils down to is rather simple.
We want the best of both worlds. The SEO boost server-side rendering provides, and the speed of a Single Page Application. All this while hosted basically for free in a serverless environment on AWS Lambda.
TL;DR Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview of what we&amp;rsquo;ll be building for you to get up to speed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>